The next set of exam topics will cover different topologies, that is, different network layouts. The most common topology for small networks is a star topology.
In a star topology, a central device, usually a switch, is the centerpiece of the network through which all other devices connect.
It is easily scalable as it is easy to plug another device into the switch.
It is also fairly fault tolerant, as a break between a device and a switch typically does not affect the rest of the network.
Of course, should the central device fail, the network will be down as there is no leftover method for the devices to connect to each other.
A mesh connection is one you see far more often in WANs than in LANs. Within a mesh connection, every device has a connection to every other device.
Again, you don't often see this in LANs. But in WANs, it is not uncommon to have every office in a WAN connected to every other office in the WAN, via dedicated lines.
This provides redundancy and ensures that each office can connect to other offices even if one of the connections fails.
For the exam, make sure you know the formula for figuring out how many connections are needed for a full mesh given a number of devices.
For example, in this diagram, four devices are present. The formula looks like this: n * (n-1) / 2 where n is the number of devices.
In this diagram, there are 4 * (4-1) / 2, or 6 connections. For a mesh with 10 devices, there would be 10 * (10-1) / 2, or 45 connections.